Kennedy, William; Papers mss132
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- The Flaming Corsage, 1993-1997; 2001; Undated; 12; 2.93 cu. ft.
  - Photocopy of Complete Draft with Author Notes, 1995 (Box 4 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - Second to Last Draft with Author Notes, Pages 1-220, 1995 (Box 4 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Second to Last Draft with Author Notes, Pages 221-271, 1995 (Box 4 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Incomplete Draft, 1995 (Box 4 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Draft with Edits, 1995 May (Box 4 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1995 (Box 5 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1-2)
  - Working Copy of Draft for Viking, Pages 1-209, 1995 (Box 5 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Working Copy of Draft for Viking, Pages 210-293, 1995 (Box 5 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Final Draft, Pages 1-186, 1995 (Box 5 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Final Draft, Pages 187-293, 1995 (Box 5 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Master Copy of Final Draft, Pages 1-186, Undated (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - Master Copy of Final Draft, Pages 187-293, Undated (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Final Draft, Pages 93-293, Undated (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Viking Draft, Pages 1-190, Undated (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Viking Draft, Pages 191-293, Undated (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Copy of John McElroy Draft, Pages 1-153, 1995 November (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Copy of John McElroy Draft, Pages 154-209, 1995 November (Box 6 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)
  - William Kennedy Rejected Cuts, Pages 1-164, Undated (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - William Kennedy Rejected Cuts, Pages 165-293, Undated (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2)
  - Copy Viking Proofs, 1995 December (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 3)
  - Selected Pages Read by the Author, Pages 1-111, Undated (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Selected Pages Read by the Author, Pages 112-227, Undated (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Audio Story Information, 1995-1996 (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Book Covers, Art, and Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)
  - Fan Mail and Reactions, 1995-1996; 2001 (Box 7 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 8)
  - Viking/Penguin Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 1)
  - Book Tour Information, 1995-1997 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 2-3)
  - Publisher's Weekly, 1996 March 04 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 4)
  - Viking Book Guide, 1996 May-1996 August (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of Proof Pages, 1996 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 6)
  - Franklin Library Edition Information, 1996 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 7)
  - Readings and Announcements, 1996; Undated (Oversized 6, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews and Profiles, 1996-1997 (Oversized 6, Folder 5)
  - Publicity Clippings and Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 8)
  - Articles and Reviews, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 9-10)
  - Spanish Reviews and Articles, 1999 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 11)
  - Two Writing Responses to William Kennedy's Novels, 1999 (Box 8 (12-The Flaming Corsage), Folder 12)
- Roscoe, 1996-2000; Undated; 13; 3.3 cu. ft.
  This series consists of manuscript drafts, edited copy, and reviews for Roscoe. Published in 2002, it is part of William Kennedy's "Albany Cycle" of novels. Opening in 1945 Albany, Roscoe centers around Roscoe Conway, a decades-long insider of the Democartic Party and the political machine in the capital city.
  - Working Drafts of You Can Imagine How Mac Felt, 1996-1997 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - Working Drafts of Chapters 1 and 2, 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2)
  - Working Drafts of Chapter 3, 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Drafts of Chapters 1-3, 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4)
  - Chapters 1-3 Rewrites and Edits, 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 5)
  - Working Drafts of Chapters 4 and 5, 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - Rewrites (Folder 1 of 3), 1998 (Box 1 (13-Roscoe), Folder 7)
  - Rewrites (Folders 2 and 3 of 3), 1998 (Box 2 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1-2)
  - Rewrites and Edited Pages (Folders 1-3 of 6), 1999 (Box 2 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3-5)
  - Rewrites and Edited Pages (Folders 4-6 of 6), 1999 (Box 3 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1-3)
  - Reading Drafts for Skidmore and AWP-WI, 1999 (Box 3 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4)
  - Rewrites, 1999 (Box 3 (13-Roscoe), Folder 5)
  - Complete Penultimate Draft, September 1999 (Box 3 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - Rewrites, 1999 (Box 4 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1-3)
  - Rewriten and Edited Pages, 2000 (Box 4 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2000 (Box 4 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - Partial Draft, Pages 1-214, January 2000 (Box 5 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - Harry Staley's Copy of Roscoe, Pages 1-214, 2000 (Box 5 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2)
  - Harry Staley's Copy of Roscoe, Pages 215-425, 2000 (Box 5 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2000 (Box 5 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4-5)
  - Chapter 5, First Computer Draft and Rewrites, 2000 (Box 5 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - "Roscoe Among the Saints" Edits and Rewrites, 2000 (Box 6 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - Rewrites and Edits (Folders 1-4 of 6), 2000 (Box 6 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits (Folders 5 and 6 of 6), 2000 (Box 7 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1-2)
  - Roscoe Reading Excerpts, 2000-2001 (Box 7 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2001 (Box 7 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4-5)
  - Revised Pages, January 2001 (Box 7 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - Paul Slovak's Copy of Penultimate Draft, Pages 1-211, 2001 (Box 8 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - Paul Slovak's Copy of Penultimate Draft, Pages 212-415, 2001 (Box 8 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2)
  - Final Draft for Viking, Pages 1-209, February 2001 (Box 8 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Final Draft for Viking, Pages 210-412, February 2001 (Box 8 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4)
  - Final Draft with Word Count, Pages 1-209 (Folder 1 of 2), February 2001 (Box 8 (13-Roscoe), Folder 5)
  - Final Draft with Word Count, Pages 210-412 (Folder 2 of 2), February 2001 (Box 9 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - Edited and Rejected Pages, 2001 (Box 9 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2)
  - Proofreader's Edited Copy of Roscoe, Pages 1-209, Undated (Box 9 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Proofreader's Edited Copy of Roscoe, Pages 210-412, Undated (Box 9 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Rough Pages, Pages 1-146 (Folder 1 of 2), June 2001 (Box 9 (13-Roscoe), Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of Rough Pages, Pages 147-292 (Folder 2 of 2), June 2001 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 1)
  - "Author's Note" Drafts, 2001 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 2001 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 3)
  - Articles and Reviews, 2001-2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 4)
  - Copy of Author's Rough Pages, Pages 1-146, January 2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 5)
  - Copy of Author's Rough Pages, Pages 147-292, January 2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 6)
  - Palace Theater Readings, January 2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 7)
  - Helen and Harry Staley Reading Notes, January 2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 8)
  - Galley Copy of Roscoe, February 2002 (Box 10 (13-Roscoe), Folder 9)
- The Albany Cycle, 1976; 1996; 2001-2002; 14; .66 cu. ft.
  In 1996 and 2002 publishers packaged together several of William Kennedy's "Albany Cycle" novels into single volumes for release in the United States and international market. In 1996 Penguin Books released Legs, Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, and Ironweed together for the first time with a new author's introduction. Six years later Scribner, an imprint of Simon & Schuster UK, published two books each containing three re-issued "Albany Cycle" novels. The first consisted of Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, Ironweed, and Very Old Bones. The second featured Quinn's Book, The Flaming Corsage, and Legs. This series includes materials related to these publications as well as a 1976 outline by Kennedy of his vision for the "Albany Cycle" of planned books, and correspondence and proposed artwork for paperback copies of "Albany Cycle" novels issued from Penguin in 2002.
  - William Kennedy's "Statement of Plans" for Albany Cycle, 1976 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 1)
  - The Albany Cycle: Introduction to Legs-Billy-Ironweed Volume, 1996 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 2)
  - Galley of Legs from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 3)
  - Galley of Billy Phelan's Greatest Game from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 4)
  - Galley of Ironweed from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 5)
  - Book Cover Matter for the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 6)
  - Drafts, Author Notes, and Preface for Albany Cycle in Paperback, 2001-2002 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 7)
  - The Albany Cycle Correspondence, Reviews, and Book Matter for Paperback Editions, 2001-2002 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 8)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book I Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, 2002 (Box 1 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 9)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book II Ironweed, 2002 (Box 2 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 1)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book III Very Old Bones, 2002 (Box 2 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 2)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book IV Quinn's Book, 2002 (Box 2 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 3)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book V The Flaming Corsage, 2002 (Box 2 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 4)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book VI Legs, 2002 (Box 2 (14-The Albany Cycle), Folder 5)
- Essays and Articles, 1963-1970; 1972; 1978-1998; 2002; Undated; 15; 2.03 cu. ft.
  Spanning several decades, this series features William Kennedy's essays and a news articles written for such varied outlets as newspapers, magazines, a city guide, a writers' cook book, a National Endowment for the Humanities Project, and a museum. In many instances, the files also include supplemental materials such as research, notes, and correspondence. Please note this series does not contain Kennedy's feature articles for the Albany Times-Union in the mid-1960s on slums, housing integration or poverty. These may be found in Series 17: Investigative Journalism.
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 1)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts, August 1990 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 2)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Notes by S. Dumbleton and Joe [Gagen], August 1990 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 3)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Author's Editing, 1990 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 4)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Author's Editing, Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 5)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Final Draft, Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 6)
  - "The Capitol in Albany," Introduction, Drafts and Final, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 7)
  - "Perry Duryea," Drafts and Author Notes for New York Times Article, 1972; Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 8)
  - Empire State College, Courses, 1990 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, Essays and Articles, 1987 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 10)
  - "Getting It All, Saving It All," Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 11)
  - Drafts of "Getting It All, Saving It All," Edited, Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 12)
  - Grandma Moses, 1963; Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and Articles Regarding Edward Hopper Publication, 1994-1995; 1997; Undated (Box 1 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 14)
  - Oversized Edward Hopper Materials, 1995; Undated (Oversized 8, Folder 1)
  - Galley Photocopy of "Edward Hopper and the American Imagination", 1995 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 1)
  - "Letter to the Reader," Zoetropes, 1999 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 2)
  - Masters of Deception, Research, 1963-1997 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 3-5)
  - Masters of Deception, Correspondence, 1997; Undated (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 6)
  - Masters of Deception, Transcribed Notes of Interviews, 1997 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 7)
  - Several Drafts of "Wag the Dog," for George Magazine, 1997 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 8)
  - Interviews and Notes Regarding "Wag the Dog," Article, 1997 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 9)
  - Travel Diary, Personal and Production Notes on "Wag the Dog", 1997 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 10)
  - "Masters of Deception"/"Wag the Dog" News Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 11)
  - "Masters of Deception" Page Proofs and Oversized Materials, 1997; Undated (Oversized 8, Folder 2)
  - "Mr. Lonely Hearts," Information, Draft, and Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 1)
  - "Negative Cooking, Negative Eating," from The Great American Writers' Cookbook, 1996-1997 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 2)
  - New Paltz, 1964; Undated (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1963 September 01-1967 December 31 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1968 January 07-1968 December 29 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1969 January 19-1969 December 28 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1970 January 04-1970 October 04 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 7)
  - News Clippings of Interest That Relate to Articles - Not Photocopied, 1963-1965 (Oversized 8, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings Written by Kennedy - Photocopied, 1965-1970 (Oversized 8, Folder 4)
  - "One Day in Albany," Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 8)
  - "One Day in Albany," Drafts, 1994 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 9)
  - "One Day in Albany," Notes, Undated (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 10)
  - "One Day in Albany," Research, 1994 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 11)
  - "One Day in Albany,"Times-Union Reprint, 1995 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 12)
  - Author Notes, Drafts and Documents Regarding Articles About Papal Visit, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 13)
  - "The Peopling of America," Research Notes, 1980 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 14)
  - "Remedios the Beauty is Alive and Well, "Newsweek Drafts and Final Piece, 2002 (Box 3 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 15)
  - "A Sense of Community," Correspondence and Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 1)
  - "A Sense of Community," Essay and Scripts, 1980 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 2)
  - "A Sense of Community," Grant Proposal, 1979 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 3)
  - "A Sense of Community," Project Updates, 1981-1982 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 4)
  - "They Who Became We," Drafts, 1980 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 5)
  - "They Who Became We," Final, 1980 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 6)
  - "Two Civilized Buildings," Drafts and Notes, 1987 (Box 4 (15-Essays and Articles), Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1950; 1959-2003; Undated; 16; .6 cu. ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains correspondence sent to William Kennedy from fellow authors, journalists, politicians, and members of the film industry. Most notably, the files document his relationships with other well-known writers of American literature, especially his decades-long friendships with mentor Saul Bellow and Hunter S. Thompson. Also included is correspondence with Philip Roth, Joyce Carol Oates, Frank McCourt, Doris Grumbach, John Updike, and more. Materials include letters, greeting cards, post cards, fax transmissions, e-mail and one Western Union mailgram. Nearly all of the other series also include correspondence related to the respective series.
  - Babenco, Hector, 1986; 1993-1994; 2003 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Banks, Russell, 1988; 1990; 1992; 1994; 2000-2002 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1964-2002 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Callaghan, Barry, 1989-1990; 1993; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Cheever, John, 1968; 1982 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1983-1984; 1986-1988; 1990-1991; 2002 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Doctorow, E.L, 1974-1993 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Foote, Shelby, 1997 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Gaddis, William, 1990 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Garcia, Marquez, Gabriel, 1992 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1969 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Grumbach, Doris, 1974; 1977-1994; 1997-2000; 2002; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1987 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Heller, Joseph, 1994 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1971-1972; 1975 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1986; 1988; 1991-1992; 1994 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Malmud, Bernard, 1963; 1966; 1981-1982 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - McCourt, Frank, 1996; 2002 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Merkin, Richard, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Montague, John, 1985-1986; 1988-1990; 1994; 1998; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Morrison, Toni, Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P, 1983-1987; 1993; 1995; 1998 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Nicholson, Jack, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1989; 1992-1995; 1999 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Percy, Walker, 1971 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Pinon, Nelida, 1988-1990 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Pinsky, Robert, 1995; 2000-2001 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Proulx, Annie, 1994-1997; 2000 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Puzo, Mario, 1980 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Quinn, Peter, 1984; 1986-1992; 1994-1996; 2002; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Rabassa, Gregory, 1987 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Rooney, Andy, 1983; 1986; 1988; 1990; 1996; 1999 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Roth, Phillip, 1987; 1991-1992 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Rushdie, Salman, 1991 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Selby, Huber, Jr, 1984; 1988 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Selzer, Dick, 1990; 1995 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Sendak, Maurice, 1998 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Shelton, Ron, 1989; 1995 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Sillitoe, Alan, 1985-1986; 1988-1990; 2002 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Smith, Red, 1950 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Stone, Robert, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Styron, William, 1973; 1986; 1988; 1993 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Talese, Gay, 1986-1987; 1989-1992; 1994; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Terkel, Studs, 1993; 1999 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Thompson, Hunter S, 1959-1965 (Box 1 (16-Correspondence), Folder 45-46)
  - Thompson, Hunter S, 1966-1971; 1973-1974; 1983; 1996-1997; 2001 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 1-2)
  - Thompson, Hunter S., Photocopies, 1959-1971; 1973-1974; 1983; 1996-1997; 2001 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 3-5)
  - Updike, John, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1970; 2000 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Wolfe, Tom, 1991 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - General, 1964; 1990; 1992; 2003 (Box 2 (16-Correspondence), Folder 10)
- Investigative Journalism, 1957-1998; Undated; 17; 2.19 cu. ft.
  This series consists of draft articles, background research materials, memos, notes, magazine and newspaper clippings on a number of subjects that William Kennedy explored and reported upon, especially for his Pulitzer Prize nominated series of features for the Albany Times-Union during the mid-1960s. Those articles included investigations into Albany slums, poverty, housing integration, and racial inequalities. While the initial copy appeared in the 1960s, the files in this series document Kennedy's continued interest and active research of the same topics in subsequent decades. Kennedy used the materials on slums as background for O Albany!. Please note the overall dates for the series are not inclusive.
  - Research Articles on Slums, Civil Rights and Housing, 1957-1988; Undated (Oversized 9, Folder 1)
  - War on Poverty Booklets and Literature, 1959; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 1)
  - Public Accommodations in Summer Resorts, 1960 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 2)
  - Housing, Rehabilitation, 1960-1961; 1965-1966; 1980; Undated (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 3)
  - Rent Control, Housing Code, Notes, Clips, Correspondence, 1961-1963; 1965 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 4)
  - Fair Housing Notes and Literature, 1961-1966; Undated (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 5-7)
  - State Commissions Brochures, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 8)
  - Urban Renewal, 1962-1963; 1972-1974 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 9)
  - Newsweek Magazine, July 29 1963 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 10)
  - Time Magazine, August 30 1963 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 11)
  - "Bombing in Birmingham,"Newsweek, September 30 1963 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 12)
  - "City Within a City," Newspaper Articles, 1963 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 13)
  - School Segregation, 1963 (Box 1 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 14)
  - Government Brochures, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 1-2)
  - The Negro in American History Curriculum Resources, 1963-1964 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 3)
  - Research Materials on Housing and Civil Rights, 1963-1966; Undated (Oversized 9, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles on Civil Rights and Housing, 1963-1991 (Oversized 9, Folder 3)
  - Intergroup Relations Booklets and Writings, 1963; 1965; Undated (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 4)
  - Housing Data, 1963; 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 5)
  - Kennedy Real Estate, Poverty, and Slum Articles, 1963; 1965-1966; Undated (Oversized 9, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1963; 1965-1967 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 6)
  - Slum Series and South End Notes, 1963; 1965; 1971; Undated (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 7)
  - The Negro and Puerto Rican in American History, 1964 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 8)
  - Information About Local Fires, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 9)
  - Proposed Civil Rights Legislation, January 6 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 10)
  - Time Magazine, March 19 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 11)
  - Newsweek Magazine, April 5 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 12)